AMRITHA.N PRABHU

Bengaluru, India 560037 | 9481008955 | amrithab11@gmail.com

Summary

Experienced Program Manager with a history of accurate & efficiently supporting Program launches for a diverse range of clientele. 5+ Years of experience product research and presenting data, risk analysis & multiple program launches across Marketplaces.

I work like a trusted advisor with skilled in research, analysis and examination of company technology and standard operating procedures. Interface and collaborate with clients and internal team members, providing consultative enhancement recommendations based on industry research. Improve existing processes, procedures, technical enhancements, resource requirements and stakeholder engagement procedures to align with strategic goals.

Skills

- Risk & compliance Management
- Program & Project Management methodologies
- People Management
- Delivering results & Meeting deadlines
- Stakeholder management
- Problem solving
- Leadership & Negotiation

Experience

Program Manager I Amazon Development center — Bengaluru, IN

Apr 2022 to Current

- Responsible for launch & maintaining of Negative seller balances & Fraud investigations processes where seller data is tracked on real time basis by allowing control fraud & abuse on online platforms using Power BI application.
- Queue management under ticketing platform(t.corp) including trend monitoring, working with stakeholders to resolve multiple issues, Ticket reporting, training SPS teams & Sev-2 & executive escalation handling along with COE summaries
- Defining project roles and responsibilities in close collaboration with the Stakeholders, including project scope and objectives to ensure a cross-functional understanding amongst project members
- Being a part of compliance operations for Product safety & Restricted products, was able to influence business decisions by identifying & reporting trends, proposing ideas which can process
- Working with Tech team to resolve seller issues related to STA pages in seller central, handling shipment queries for Inbound process for Multi-channel fulfilment across US/CA Marketplaces
- Responsible for driving Quality progress of 300 members in Compliance Operations by initiating Internal Audit, RCAs, Training & coaching. Handling disputes between Quality & Ops team, analyzing trends and collecting CAPA from worldwide nodes

- Managing HNI seller/Vendor accounts. Providing coaching on maintaining good account health
- SOP creation and handling. Was able to successfully create 25 product level SOPs and 8 process level SOPs worldwide which was then handed over to SPS teams along with conducting training to seller facing teams to handle issues and locate accurate SOPs before reaching to our queue
- Reaching out to cross functional teams to understand the areas of growth, expanding horizons by utilizing transcripts to implement case studies into real time work.
- Reduced queue volume by 35% during peak by identifying low hanging SIMs and proposing 24hrs coverage which added as a merit and helped sellers to get faster resolution with improved SLA from 48hrs first touch to 24hrs TAT
- Assessing risk management policies and protocols; making recommendations and implementing modifications and improvements. Developing models and contingency plans to deal with potential threats.
- Was responsible for Launching programs by working with multiple internal teams including Prod, Dev Ops & Finance and was successfully able role a launch 4 process (Medical devices, Toys, Batteries, Inflatables) from planning to implementation
- Direct day to day operations focused on attainment of key business metrics continuous improvement initiative and an eight-member team with related direct reports
- On-boarding In-house talents who were interested to move in technical grounds and formed a team of four & titled as "Business support engineers"
- Amplify organizational quality standards by delivering 92% increased quality during 3
 year timeframe. During the start quality data stood at 70% on 2023 which was then
 accelerated by 22% improved quality by Q2 2024
- Worked with tech teams to create a repository tool embodied with Java & Python script to track new updates, SOPs, flowcharts and also introduced query mechanism using Chat-BOT and aligned top performing associates to respond to the queries by associates. This improved our first touch SLA to 95% when averaged out for 6 months. Accelerating efficiency of operations by assisting with controlled budgets, overseeing seller accounts, managing and schedule & driving meetings
- Responsible for creating score card for L3 population. Delegating projects for FLS
 candidates and issuing coaching plan for folks who need Improvement. Creating
 yearly forte discussions to assigned team and working with HR partners to align on
 hike discussions for L3 span.
- Looking into Multichannel fulfillment queue, handling Sev-2 escalations, visiting onsite to drive improvements in FCs. Looking into shipment queries for account managed sellers.

Process Executive Oct 2016 to Jun 2017 INFOSYS LTD — Bengaluru, IN

- Call monitoring and training teams on handling Quality conversations with customers
- Increased annual revenue(\$3800~) by recommending improvements in efficiency by achieving over and above the target level
- Answered telephone or online requests and completed interactions quickly to meet productivity goals

Senior Officer
ICICI Pvt Limited — Bengaluru, IN

Feb 2016 to Sep 2016

- Expertise in handling end-to-end banking operations with finacle software
- Handling international remittance, repatriations and financial advisory for resident and nonresident customer.
- Handled NRI portfolio and generated 35% of CASA requirement for entire branch in first 6 months joining.
- Managing institutional and retail customer portfolio and generating leads for investment and handling HNI customer requests as a relationship manager.
- Promoted products or services to each customer to consistently achieve sales targets
 providing validation support to external auditors & concurrent auditors along with backoffice counterparts for their ad hoc requests.
- Executed customer transactions, including deposits, withdrawals, money orders and Cheques
- Handled Products such as Home loan & Gold loans which generated revenue to the branch

Education and Training

PGDBO, Banking Operation

Jan 2016

NIIT - Mangalore

B.com, Financial Accounting

Jul 2015

Canara First Grade Degree College — Mangalore

Accomplishments

- Was awarded as "Employee of the year" in the year 2020
- Awarded as "Beyond" for the year 2021 for strategic innovations
- Awarded with a certificate for meeting targets & achieving highest productivity for Q1 & Q2' 2020
- Received accolade from Account managers & Clients for Bias for action & Delivering results

Activities

- Contributed to the training for under-privileged students on language subjects
 Tutoring & mentoring post metric candidates in and around Mangalore
- Conducted a seminar for pre-metric students on educating 'women hygiene & safety'